SAEID DOROUDI

Software Engineer

Tehran, IR | https://saeiddoroudi.ir +989144786806 | sdoroudi@mafpars.com

GitHub | LinkedIn | StackOverflow

Software engineer with 10+ years' experience in multiple businesses from small startups to manage software projects in large scale companies. Challenge lover and every day learner, love to contribute to open-source projects and do more.

SKILLS

- Back-End | C# | .Net | ASP.Net | OOP | SQL Server | Redis | NoSQL | Testing | RabbitMQ | CI/CD | Docker | Kubernetes.
- Front-End | JavaScript | TypeScript | Vue.js | PWA | React | Ionic | jQuery | HTML | CSS | Angular | Blazor | SSR/SSG | Cypress.
- Micro-Services | DDD | Azure | Git | Scrum | K6 | OAuth | GraphQL | gRPC | Speck in Turkish, Persian and English.

EXPERIENCES

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

HyperStar(MafPars) | Tehran

2021 - PRESENT

- Building multiple back-office applications for multiple parts of organization such as HR, eCommerce, Finance and Suppliers to achieve up to 40% cost saving and digitalizing manual process.
- Building Customers Loyalty mobile application (Flutter) and lottery system to make customers loyal and have better experience.
- Building scalable microservices based on .Net and use Kubernetes as Infrastructure for achieving zero down time deployment.
- Integrate DB2 based system that doesn't provide real-time update with Online shopping channels like Snapp Shop, Digikala.
- Providing Supplier Portal and integrate it with BPMS software, gains lot of cost and paper saving with automating ordering.
- Find performance bottlenecks using Performance Testing, implement test processes for critical business sections using BDD.
- Implement Front-End infrastructure using Vue.Js 3 and TypeScript and update all front-end apps to new structure.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Mobinnet | Tehran

2018 - 2021

- Build Mobinnet eCare Mobile app using PWA and Asp.Net Core, Vue which responds to more than 70% of requests beside web
 version after a little while.
- Find Performance issues and design new structure for existing eCare System using .Net Core, CQRS, Redis, Kafka, HA Proxy, Azure DevOps witch results in 99.99% uptime system.
- Implement modem troubleshoot application using lonic to help customers to find and fix their internet connectivity issues.

MOBILE DEVELOPER

ArtinMehr | Tabriz

2017 - 2018

• Build 3 Ionic based shopping mobile applications for local shopping centers and deploy them to Google Play and AppStore.

CO-FOUNDER, DEVELOPER

Elca | Marand

2015 - 2017

- Build SMS based Lottery System for food industry factories and build simpler version for restaurants using Asp.Net and Angular.
- Build TeleHub (Telegram Directory App) Mobile Application and Service and publish it to AppStore and Windows Store.
- Build Iran Football League Mobile app using Java and publish it to Bazaar and reach thousands active users.
- Implement Factory Production process management WinForms based system for customer (SahandZoob).
- Implement Telegram bots for controlling IoT based systems based on Raspberry PI.
- Building multiple IoT based applications and RFID based entrance control systems.

FREELANCER 2007 – 2013

- Build Abna-News Agency QA Multilingual (5 Languages) website.
- Build Application for managing Tax for municipality of Marand.
- Build Websites and Applications for BlogSky, IranArmy, Tabriz University, Hoopa, Barayand Publishing, and many other clients.
- Build ThemeStudio website and sell blog themes and get orders to develop Websites.

EDUCATION AND AWARDS

Bachelor of Software Engineering technologies Tabriz University of College
1st place in 3rd national congress of electronic content in solo section in Iran Tehran

2010-2013

2008